

Talat Rahman Miah

Nationality: Bangladeshi Date of birth: 25/11/1995

Company Series Company Series Comp

Website: https://talatrahman.github.io/Portfolio/

• Home: 10/9 Muslimnagar , Matuail , Demra Dhaka, 1362 Dhaka (Bangladesh)

ABOUT ME

As a **Tech Professional** to enter in a well-reputed organization in a suitable position, having the intention to work with **honesty** and **sincerity**, to learn grow and eventually take greater responsibilities and to face the challenge of the time to gain experience and skills for a successful career

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior WordPress Developer

Bengal Byte, Germany [08/2024 - Current]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://bengalbyte.net/

- Developed and maintained the company's Website, increasing online sales by 25%.
- Implemented a mobile-first design strategy, improving mobile traffic by 30%.
- Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to enhance user experience and functionality.
- Managed version control using Git and conducted code reviews

Web Development Project Manager

Website's Farmer, Bangladesh [06/2024 – 08/2024]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://websitesfarmer.com/

- Leading teams to deliver projects on time, within scope, and on budget
- Worked closely with developers and designers
- Contributed to the design and implementation of front-end interfaces.
- Provided ongoing support and maintenance for websites

Software Engineer (Wp)

SELISE, Switzerland [03/2021 – 01/2024]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://selisegroup.com/ | Name of unit or department: Web

- Advance front-end Design convert from figma and Psd
- WordPress Website development and maintenance with Elementor
- Website's Security advancements
- Server management Cloudways, AWS etc.

Software Engineer

Olympic Development Ltd, Bangladesh [09/2020 - 03/2021]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://greeho.com/

- Company real state business website development in WordPress
- Theme customization & Security enhancement
- · Aws server maintenance, Site load balancing
- Responsive HTML, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap

IT Executive & Web master

TravelPro Trs Ltd, Bangladesh [10/2019 - 03/2020]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://travelpro-trs.com/

Email address: info@travelpro-trs.com

- Company WordPress website management
- IT work support

Internship

Sonali Bank Ltd, Bangladesh [04/2019 – 07/2019]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://www.sonalibank.com.bd/

- Travel website development
- Development tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 5, Php

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor in Computer Science

Independent University Bangladesh [2014 – 2020]

Address: Plot 16, Block B, Aftabuddin Ahmed Road Bashundhara Residential Area, Dhaka, Bangladesh, 1245 Dhaka (Bangladesh) | **Website:** http://iub.ac.bd/ | **Level in EQF:** EQF level 6

Google Project Management Specialization

Google (Coursera) [04/08/2024 – 11/10/2024]

Website: https://www.coursera.org/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Introduction to Project Management

IBM [01/08/2024 - 11/08/2024]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://www.coursera.org/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

PCAP - Python Certification Course

Kodekloud [05/08/2024 – 21/09/2024]

Website: https://kodekloud.com/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

GitLab CI/CD: Architecting, Deploying, and Optimizing Pipelines

KodeKloud [06/09/2024 - 21/09/2024]

Website: https://kodekloud.com/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Google AI Essentials

Google [10/08/2024 - 30/08/2024]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://www.coursera.org/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Github Actions Certification

Kodekloud [05/09/2024 - 21/09/2024]

Website: https://kodekloud.com/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

SEO Training Masterclass 2024: Beginner To Advanced SEO

Udemy [20/08/2024 – 10/09/2024]

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Website: https://www.udemy.com/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Fundamental of DevOps

KodeKloud [10/09/2024 – 21/09/2024]

Website: https://kodekloud.com/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Bengali

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Web Development: HTML / CSS / Bootstrap / Javascript / PHP / DevOps: AWS, Git. / Third-party API integration / Photoshop And Figma / Responsive Designs / Frontend Development (HTML,CSS, JavaScript) / CMS (Wordpress, Shopify) / SEO-Management / Online communication (Slack, Trello, Discord, GatherTown, Google)

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: A **Driving Licence:** B

As a Senior WordPress Developer with 5 years of experience, I specialize in building high-performance websites using custom themes and optimizing for SEO. My focus is on creating user-friendly, scalable, and secure solutions. I'm eager to contribute my expertise to drive success in your projects.

Talat Rahman Miah

Tolat Rahman